Paul Conrad Cartoons
Paul Conrad Cartoons
1963-1969
Conrad, Paul, 1924-2010.
8.1 linear ft.
Approximately 1,089 original editorial cartoons by the Pulitzer Prize-winning American cartoonist primarily from the Los Angeles Times with some from the Denver Post.
2642890
Biographical History
Paul Conrad (1924-2010) was an American Pulitzer Prize winning editorial cartoonist.
Paul Francis Conrad was born on June 27, 1924 in Cedar Rapids, Iowa. During World War II, Conrad served with the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and he received a B.A. in art from the University of Iowa in 1950, where he contributed cartoons to college paper, the Daily Iowan. Growing up in Iowa, Conrad was inspired by Jay Norwood "Ding" Darling’s cartoons in the Des Moines Register. From 1950 to 1964, Conrad was the editorial cartoonist at the Denver Post with his work distributed by the Hall Syndicate. He left the Denver Post for the Los Angeles Times.
Conrad joined the Los Angeles Times several years after Otis Chandler became publisher, marking an era of change in which the newspaper's editorial page began to voice more liberal viewpoints and the paper worked to increase its visibility and expand its influence, which sparked criticism from more conservative members of the famed Chandler family. Conrad's cartoons were part of that new direction. His work was also syndicated through the Los Angeles Times Syndication. Conrad remained with the Los Angeles Times until 1993 when he accepted a buyout after changes to the paper's management took place, with the Chandler family no longer having a connection to the paper.
Conrad was renowned for his bold depictions and in particular his caricatures of Richard Nixon during Watergate. Conrad's work angered Nixon and other politicians: he was named on Nixon's infamous enemies list and Los Angeles mayor Sam Yorty brought a libel suit against Conrad in 1968. Ironically, Conrad would later hold the Richard M. Nixon Lecture Chair at Whittier College from 1977 to 1978.
Conrad won his first Pulitzer Prize in 1964 for his work at the Denver Post and received two additional Pulitzer prizes in 1971 and 1984. Conrad was also a Pulitzer Prize finalist in 1998. Sigma Delta Chi presented several awards to him (1953, 1969, 1971, 1981-1982, 1996). His many other recognitions include seven Distinguished Service Awards by the Society of Professional Journalists and four Robert F. Kennedy Journalism Awards (1985, 1990, 1992-1993).
Several compilations of Conrad’s cartoons have been published including Pro and Conrad (1979), Drawn and Quartered (1985) and his autobiography, I, Con: the autobiography of Paul Conrad, editorial cartoonist (2006). The PBS Independent Lens documentary released in 2006, PAUL CONRAD: Drawing Fire, explored Conrad's 50 year career. Also a sculptor, Conrad's bronze works of political leaders were exhibited at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art.
Paul Conrad lived in Rancho Palos Verdes, California and continued to draw editorial cartoons into his 80s, which were distributed by the Tribune Media Syndicate. He died at his home on September 4, 2010.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Paul Conrad Cartoons contain approximately 1,089 original editorial cartoons from 1963 to 1969. The cartoons from 1963 as well as several from 1964 date to Conrad's time at the Denver Post. The remaining the cartoons (the bulk of the collection) were published by the Los Angeles Times.
Conrad commented primarily on national and world affairs with some attention directed towards California politics and Los Angeles mayor Sam Yorty. Conrad provided extensive commentary on the presidency of Lyndon B. Johnson and the Vietnam War’s increasing escalation under Johnson’s order. With the election of Ronald Reagan as California Governor, Conrad’s attention to California politics becomes a more common theme and Reagan's hopes at becoming a viable presidential candidate (and the influence of Reagan's past as an actor) are chronicled. Conrad, drawing for a California paper, explored the influence of the Sunbelt on American politics and also chronicled the emergence of the right wing faction of the Republican Party, going so far as to refer to them as “kooks” in more than one cartoon. While famous for his portrayals of Richard Nixon during the Watergate scandal, that period of Conrad's work is not represented in this collection. However, this collection offers examples of Conrad's earlier treatment of Richard Nixon as his gained political strength leading up to the 1968 presidential election.
While known to take liberal positions on issues, no particular political party or figure was immune from Conrad's bold depictions. For example, in cartoons about the civil rights movement, Conrad is both critical of southern, white supremacists as well as the shift among some activists to black nationalism. Conrad’s treatment of events also went beyond the surface of such issues. His civil rights cartoons are evidence of this. While critical of urban race riots and the new emphasis on black militancy in mid to late 1960s, Conrad also produced cartoons that explored possible roots of such problems such as a lack of education and poverty. His coverage of the Poor People’s Campaign in 1968 represents Conrad's attention to topics absent from other cartoonists' considerations during this era.
Conrad also frequently utilized people and themes from popular culture in his caricatures. Political figures like Ronald Reagan and Hubert Humphrey were transformed into Peanuts and Disney characters. Other figures appear in literary allusions to Shakespeare’s works. He also juxtaposed references to the counterculture with political events and figures: Robert F. Kennedy appeared as a long haired Maharishi Mahesh Yogi figure in a transcendental mediation pose and the band Jefferson Airplane became the “Jeffersonian Airplane”.
Each cartoon is dated and bears a mark of the syndicate which distributed it. The cartoons were drawn with pen, ink and crayon on illustration board and measure approximately 11 ½" x 14". The captions are typically written on the cartoon in pencil, however several have been printed and pasted on. The bottom border of the cartoons generally have notations and numbers in pencil related to the cartoon's production in print. One color cartoon is in the collection, (July 12, 1964) and appears to have been created for and aired on NBC television. It depicts the potential Republican presidential candidates during the 1964 election as feathers on the iconic NBC peacock.
Arrangement of the Collection
The cartoons are arranged in chronological order and foldered by month. Cartoons with specific years but without specific months and days are located at the beginning of that year's folders.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Conrad, Paul, 1924-2010.; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Ho Chi Minh, 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; McNamara, Robert S., 1916-2009. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Reagan, Ronald -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Yorty, Sam, 1909-1998 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Register and Tribune Syndicate.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Los Angeles times.; Denver post.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- California -- Los Angeles.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- California -- Los Angeles.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Demonstrations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- California -- Los Angeles.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nuclear weapons -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Peace -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Poverty -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Public welfare -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Pulitzer Prizes.; Space Exploration -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1963-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Paul Conrad, 1969.
Inventory
- Cartoons, 11 1/4" X 14"; Click here for a detailed inventory.; See below for an index to the cartoons.
  - 1963 (Denver Post) (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - 1964 ( Denver Post) (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - Feb 1964 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - Mar 1964 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - Apr 1964 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - May 1964 (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - Jun 1964 (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
  - Jul 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - Aug 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
  - Sep 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
  - Oct 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - Nov 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
  - Dec 1964 (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - Jan 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - Feb 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - Mar 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - Apr 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - May 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
  - Jun 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - Jul 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
  - Aug 1965 (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
  - Sep 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
  - Oct 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
  - Nov 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
  - Dec 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
  - Jan 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
  - Feb 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
  - Mar 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
  - Apr 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - May 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - Jun 1966 (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - Jul 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  - Aug 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
  - Sep 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
  - Oct 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
  - Nov 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
  - Dec 1966 (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
  - Jan 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
  - Feb 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
  - Mar 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
  - Apr 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
  - May 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
  - Jun 1967 (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
  - Jul 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - Aug 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - Sep 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - Oct 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - Nov 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - Dec 1967 (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - Jan 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
  - Feb 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
  - Mar 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
  - Apr 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
  - May 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - Jun 1968 (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
  - Jul 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
  - Aug 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
  - Sep 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
  - Oct 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
  - Nov 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
  - Dec 1968 (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
  - Jan 1969 (Oversize 10, Folder 7)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
abortion B7F3-B7F4
Addonizio, Hugh J. B8F1
Adenauer, Konrad B7F4
AFL-CIO B1F6 B2F3
Africa B2F6
Agnew, Spiro T. B10F2-B10F5
Alabama B3F1 B3F3 B4F2 B7F4 B7F6
Ali, Muhammad B7F4
aluminum industry B4F3
American Bar Association B6F4
American Federation of Television and Radio Artists B7F3
American Independent Party B10F5
American Indians B8F1 B9F1 B10F1
American Legion B1F5
American Medical Association B1F4 B2F6-B3F1 B3F3 B5F1
anarchy B2F1 B8F6 B10F3 B10F6
Anderson, Merle B5F3
anti-missile systems B7F3 B8F3
anti-Semitism B10F3
anti-trust laws B4F1
Appalachia B2F5
Argentina B6F5
armed forces B1F1 B3F2 B3F4 B4F2 B4F4 B6F1 B8F2 B9F3
Asia B7F5 B8F3
Asian flu B5F2
Association of American Physicians and Surgeons B3F8
auto industry B1F4 B5F5 B6F3 B7F3 B8F3-B8F4
automation B3F1
Baker, Bobby B1F2-B1F4 B1F6 B3F3 B5F1 B5F4 B7F1-B7F2
Ballets Africains B10F4
banking industry B6F2 B7F3
Barnard, Christiaan B9F1
Beame, Abe B4F2-B4F3
beef industry B8F5
Benson, Ezra Taft B1F3
Biao, Marshall Lin B6F3 B6F5 B7F1
Bill of Rights B1F6
black nationalism B2F1 B5F6 B10F2 B10F5-B10F6
Black Panthers B5F6 B9F1
black power B5F6-B6F1 B6F4-B6F5 B8F5-B8F6 B10F4
Bliss, Ray B7F5
Bocheng, Liu B7F1
boycotts B8F5 B10F2
Bracero Program B3F2
Brezhnev, Leonid Ilyich B2F4-B2F5 B3F1 B3F7 B5F1 B5F3 B6F5 B7F5-B7F6 B10F3
Brinkley, David B7F3
Britain B1F3 B1F6 B2F4 B6F4 B8F5
Brooke, Edward W. B10F6
Brown Sr., Edmund Gerald B5F3 B5F6 B6F4-B6F5
Brown, H. Rap B8F3
Brunage, Avery B10F4
Buddhist monks B2F5 B5F5
budget B3F1 B4F3 B5F1 B6F5 B7F1 B8F4
Bundy, McGeorge B3F1
Bureau of Reclamation B5F6
California B1F4 B1F6-B1F7 B3F1 B3F4 B4F4 B5F3 B5F5 B6F5-B7F4 B8F3-B9F1 B9F5-B9F6 B10F4-B10F7
Canada B5F4
capital punishment B7F3-B7F4 B8F1
Carlson, Paul B2F5
Carmichael, Stokely B6F5 B7F6
cartoonists B2F3 B3F5
Castro, Fidel B1F2 B4F2
censorship B3F4
Central Intelligence Agency B2F3 B3F5 B7F2 B8F5
Chaney, James B1F7
China B1F2 B2F3-B2F4 B3F4 B4F3 B5F3 B6F1 B6F4 B6F6-B7F1 B8F2-B8F3
civil rights B1F1 B1F4-B1F5 B1F7-B2F1 B2F6 B3F4 B3F7 B4F2-B5F1 B5F6-B6F1 B6F3 B7F3 B8F2 B9F4
Clark, James S. B3F3
coal industry B6F4
communism B1F3 B2F4 B4F3 B8F5 B9F5 B10F4
Congo B2F1 B2F3 B2F5
Congress B1F1 B1F3 B2F1 B2F3 B3F1 B3F3-B3F4 B4F1 B5F1-B5F2 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4 B7F1-B7F2 B7F4 B8F1-B8F2 B9F2-B9F3 B10F3
Congress of Racial Equality B1F7
Connor, Chuck B6F5
cost of living B6F2
counterculture B8F4
crime B9F2
Cuba B1F3-B1F4 B4F2 B9F2
Cuban Missile Crisis B2F3
Cummins Prison Farm B9F2
Cyprus B1F4 B2F3
Czechoslovakia B10F1-B10F3
Daley, Richard J. B9F4 B10F3
de Gaulle, Charles B1F2 B1F4 B1F6 B2F1 B2F3 B2F5-B3F1 B3F3 B3F5 B4F4-B5F4 B5F6 B6F2-B6F3 B7F4 B7F6-B8F1 B8F3 B8F5-B9F1 B9F3 B9F5 B10F1 B10F5
democracy B5F5 B6F6-B7F1
Democratic National Convention B10F1-B10F2
Democratic Party B1F4-B1F6 B2F2 B5F3 B7F1 B8F6 B10F1-B10F2
demonstrations B2F6 B3F4 B4F2-B4F4 B5F4 B5F6 B7F4 B8F1-B8F3 B8F6 B10F2 B10F5
Dirksen, Everett B1F6-B1F7 B2F3 B3F8 B5F1 B5F4 B5F6 B6F3 B7F1 B9F2
Disney, Walt B6F6
Dodd, Thomas B5F4-B6F1 B7F3-B7F4 B7F6-B8F1
Dominican Republic B3F5 B4F1
Douglas, William O. B6F4
draft B4F2 B4F4 B6F6 B7F2-B7F3 B8F4 B8F6
drug industry B7F5
drug use B5F5 B7F5 B8F2
Dulles, John Foster B2F1 B7F4
economy B3F1 B5F4 B7F3
Eisenhower, Dwight B1F6 B2F1 B2F3-B2F4 B7F5
elections B1F3-B1F6 B2F1 B2F4 B2F6 B5F3 B5F5 B6F1-B6F3 B6F5 B8F2-B8F4 B9F1 B9F4-B9F6 B10F4
En-lai, Chou B7F1
Erhard, Ludwig B3F3 B4F4 B6F3
espionage B3F2 B5F3 B6F5 B10F5
ethics B1F3 B1F6-B1F7 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4 B7F2 B8F1
Europe B3F4 B5F5
Faisal of Saudi Arabia B5F6
Fanfani, Amintore B4F4
farm workers B10F2
farming B1F3 B2F6 B3F4
fascism B10F3
Federal Bureau of Investigation B2F5 B3F5
Federal Communications Commission B3F1 B3F3
Federal Reserve B3F3 B6F2 B8F4
Florida B7F6
Food and Drug Administration B5F5
Ford, Gerald R. B2F6 B3F8 B5F1 B5F4 B7F1
foreign policy B1F3-B1F5 B2F5-B3F1 B3F4 B4F1 B6F1 B8F2
Formosa B7F1
Fortas, Abraham B10F3-B10F4
France B3F7 B4F4 B5F3 B6F2 B10F5
free speech B2F6 B3F3 B8F2
Fulbright, J. William B1F5 B3F1 B6F1 B9F2
Garrison, Jim B6F5 B8F6-B9F1
Georgia B6F4
Germany B1F1 B2F3 B2F5 B3F3 B6F5 B7F4 B7F6 B10F3 B10F5
gerrymandering B3F3
Ghandi, Indira B5F1
Gleason, Teddy B3F1
Glenn, John B1F4
gold B3F1 B3F3 B8F5-B8F6 B9F3
Goldberg, Arthur B9F2 B9F4
Goldwater, Barry B1F1 B1F3-B2F6 B4F3 B5F1 B6F3 B6F6 B7F3 B9F5
government representation B1F3
grain and chemical interests B7F5
Grand Canyon B5F6
Great Society B2F5 B3F1 B3F3-B3F4
Greece B8F6
Gromyko, Andrei B5F4
Gronouski, John A. B3F4
Groppi, James B8F3
Guam B7F4
Guantanamo B1F2
Guinea B5F3
gun lobby B6F4 B9F5
guns (including control of) B9F1 B9F4-B10F1
Halleck, Charles B2F6 B5F1
Hamilton, George B8F3
Hand, Lloyd B5F3
Harriman, W. Averell B9F5
Head Start B3F6
Hershey, Lewis B. B4F4
higher education B7F1-B7F2 B7F4 B9F2 B9F5 B10F5
Hitler, Adolph B10F4
Ho Chi Minh B4F4-B5F1 B6F1 B6F6 B7F2-B7F3 B8F3-B8F4 B9F1-B9F3
Hoffa, Jimmy B1F4 B6F1 B6F6 B8F2
holidays B4F4 B6F6 B7F5 B8F6
Hoover, J. Edgar B2F3-B2F5 B7F2 B9F4
housing B5F6-B6F1 B6F3 B7F4 B8F3 B9F2
HUAAC B4F2 B6F2
Humphrey, Hubert B2F2 B4F4 B5F2-B5F3 B5F5 B6F1 B7F4 B8F5 B9F4-B10F5
Hungary B10F1-B10F2
hunger B9F4 B10F2
Huntley, Chet B7F3
immigration B3F1
India B5F2
Indonesia B4F2 B9F5
inflation B5F1 B5F4 B6F2-B6F3 B8F4
integration B1F6 B2F4 B3F5 B4F1 B7F6 B10F5
Internal Revenue Service B3F4 B5F6
International Longshoresmen's Union B3F1
interstate commerce B2F6
Israel B7F6 B8F1-B8F2
Japan B5F2
Jenkins, Walter B2F4
John Birch Society B2F4 B4F1 B4F4 B5F2 B9F6
Johnson, Lady Bird B2F2 B2F5-B2F6 B3F4 B7F5 B8F6 B9F3 B10F4
Johnson, Luci B. B2F6 B4F3 B5F6 B6F2 B7F2 B8F6-B9F1
Johnson, Lyndon Baines SEE ALL FOLDERS
justice department B3F4 B5F3 B6F3 B6F5
Kashmir B5F1
Keller, Helen B9F6
Kennedy, Jacqueline B6F6 B7F4
Kennedy, John F. B2F3 B9F4 B9F6
Kennedy, Robert F. B2F1-B2F2 B2F5 B3F3 B4F3 B5F2-B5F3 B5F6 B6F2 B7F2-B7F3 B7F5 B8F1 B8F4 B8F6-B9F6
Kennedy, Ted B2F5 B4F2 B5F3 B10F2
Khan, Ayub B4F1 B4F4
Khanh, Nguyen B2F3 B2F6
Khrushchev, Nikita B1F1-B1F2 B1F4-B1F5 B2F2 B2F4
Kiesinger, Kurt Georg B6F5
King Jr., Martin Luther B3F2-B3F4 B3F8-B4F1 B5F6-B6F1 B9F3-B9F4 B9F6
Klein, Julius B6F1
Korean War B3F4 B9F1 B9F3
Kosygin, Alexey B2F4-B2F5 B3F1 B3F7 B5F4 B6F5 B7F5-B7F6 B8F3 B8F5
Ku Klux Klan B2F2 B3F3-B3F5 B4F2-B4F4 B10F4
Kuchel, Thomas B7F4 B9F2
Ky, Nguyen Cao B5F5 B6F1 B7F3 B8F2 B10F5
labor B3F1 B3F5 B5F2
Laird, Melvin R. B5F4
Lane, Mark B7F5
Latin America B7F4 B10F1
law and order B10F1-B10F3 B10F5
Lemay, Curtis B5F2 B10F4
Lenin, Vladimir B2F5
Life (magazine) B2F4
Lindsay, John B3F6 B4F3 B8F4 B10F4
Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot B1F4-B1F5 B1F7-B2F1
Lomax, Louis B6F6
Long, Edward V. B8F2
Long, Russell B3F1 B7F6
Luce, Clare Booth B2F4
MacArthur, Douglas B3F4
Maddox, Lester B6F4
Makarios III B1F4 B2F3
Malcolm X B3F2
Mansfield, Mike B1F5
Marshall, Thurgood B7F6
McCarthy, Eugene B7F1 B8F5-B9F1 B9F3-B9F5 B10F2 B10F4
McCarthy, Joseph B5F5 B7F1
McDivitt, James A. B3F6
McDonald, David J. B3F4
McGovern, George B10F2
McHugh, Simon and Vicki B8F1
McNamara, Robert B1F3-B1F4 B4F3-B4F4 B5F4 B6F1 B7F3 B8F1 B8F3 B8F5 B9F2
Medicare B2F3 B2F5-B3F1 B3F4 B3F8 B4F2 B6F1
mental health B7F3-B7F4 B8F5
Meredith, James B5F6
Mexico B5F4 B8F3
Middle East B1F6 B3F3 B7F5-B8F2
Mills, Wilbur B9F5
Milwaukee, Wisconsin B8F3
Mississippi B2F3 B2F6 B3F3-B3F4 B4F1 B5F6 B6F3 B8F4 B10F1
Mississippi River B3F4
Morrisey, Frank B4F2
Morse, Wayne B5F2 B9F2
Moyers, Bill B4F2 B5F6 B6F6
Munsinger Affair B5F3
Murphey, George B8F2
Muskie, Edmund B10F3
Nader, Ralph B5F5
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B1F6 B3F1 B7F6-B8F2 B8F4
National Park Service B7F4
National Rifle Association B7F5 B8F1 B9F4-B9F6
National States Rights Party B8F2
NATO B2F5 B4F1 B5F3-B5F6 B10F5
Nazism B4F4 B6F2 B6F4-B6F5 B8F2
Nehru, Jawaharlal B1F6
neutrality B1F5
New Orleans B4F1
New York B2F2 B2F4 B3F2-B3F3
New York City B2F1 B3F6 B4F2 B5F1 B5F4 B7F4 B10F4-B10F5
Newark, New Jersey B8F1
Nixon, Pat B3F8 B10F2
Nixon, Richard M. B1F1 B1F4-B1F5 B1F7 B2F4 B3F8 B6F2 B6F5 B7F3 B7F6 B8F4 B9F1-B9F6 B10F2-B10F6
Nkrumah, Kwame B5F3
non-violence B6F1
North Korea B9F1
nuclear weapons B1F7 B2F2-B2F4 B3F7 B5F2-B5F3 B5F5 B6F3-B6F4 B7F2 B8F4-B8F5 B9F6 B10F4
oil and gasoline B5F4 B7F3 B7F5 B8F4
Olympics B8F5 B10F4
O'Malley, Robert B6F6
organ transplants B9F1
Organization of American States B3F5
organized crime B3F3
Oswald, Lee Harvey B1F3
Pakistan B3F5
Panama B1F4 B2F6
peace B4F4-B5F2 B5F4 B6F4 B6F6-B7F3 B8F1 B8F6 B9F2 B9F4 B10F4-B10F5
Peace and Freedom Party B9F1
Percy, Charles H. B8F4
Philadelphia B2F3
police B2F6
police brutality B8F4 B10F3
politics B1F6 B3F8 B2F4 B6F3
pollution B1F2 B8F3-B8F4
Poor People's Campaign B9F5-B9F6
Pope Paul VI B4F2 B5F4 B8F6
poverty B3F1 B3F6 B5F1 B6F5
Powell, Adam Clayton B3F4 B6F3 B6F5 B7F1-B7F4 B7F6-B8F1
prayer in schools B1F6 B6F3
press B2F3 B5F2 B5F4 B6F1-B6F2 B6F4 B6F6 B10F2
Quill, Michael B5F1
racism B1F6 B2F1 B3F8 B7F5 B8F6 B10F3
Rafferty, Max B9F2
railroad industry B7F5
Reagan, Nancy B8F2
Reagan, Ronald B5F1 B5F3 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4 B6F6-B7F4 B7F6-B10F2
real estate lobby B5F6-B6F1 B9F4
Redwoods B7F4-B7F5 B9F2 B9F6
Republican Nominating Convention B10F1
Republican Party B1F4-B2F2 B2F4-B2F6 B3F8 B4F3-B5F3 B6F3 B6F5 B7F3-B7F5 B8F5-B8F6 B9F3-B9F4 B10F1-B10F2
Reuther, Walter B1F4
Rhodesia B5F4
right to work law B3F5
right-wing extremists B2F4 B6F5 B7F2-B7F4 B10F3
riots B1F4 B2F1 B3F8 B5F6-B6F1 B7F6-B8F3 B9F2-B9F4
Rockefeller, Nelson B1F4-B1F5 B7F6 B8F2 B8F4 B9F1-B9F3 B9F5 B10F6
Rockwell, George Lincoln B8F2
Rolleston, Moreton B2F4
Romney, George W. B6F6 B7F3 B8F2-B8F4 B9F1
Roosevelt, Franklin D. B3F4
Rostow, Walt Whitman B9F1
Ruby, Jack B6F4
Rumford Act B8F6 B9F4-B9F5
Rusk, Dean B2F3 B9F2
Russell, Bertrand B7F5
Russia B3F1 B3F4 B3F7 B5F1 B5F3 B6F1 B7F3 B8F4 B9F6 B10F4
Salinger, Pierre B1F4
Salisbury, Harrison B7F1
San Francisco State College B10F5-B10F6
schools B6F3 B7F3
Scranton, William B1F7-B2F1 B10F6
Securities and Exchange Commission B10F6
segregation B1F1 B6F3
Shastri, Lal Bahadur B4F1 B4F4-B5F1
Shriver, Sargent B8F5
Sierra Club B5F6
silver B3F3
Sinyavsky, Andrei B5F2
social security B6F4
South America B2F3
Soviet Union B1F3 B2F4-B2F5 B5F2 B7F2 B8F3-B8F4 B10F2
space exploration B1F2 B2F2 B2F4 B3F2-B3F3 B3F5-B3F8 B4F3-B4F4 B5F2-B5F4 B6F3 B6F5-B6F6 B7F2 B7F4-B7F5 B8F4-B8F5 B10F3 B10F5
Spock, Benjamin B9F1
sports B3F1 B4F1-B4F2 B6F6
Stalin, Joseph B10F2
Stalin, Svetlana B7F3-B7F4
steel industry B2F6 B3F4 B5F1
Stevenson, Adlai E. B1F5 B2F6
strikes B3F1 B5F4 B6F1 B6F3 B6F6 B7F3 B7F5 B8F3 B10F4
Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee B5F5 B6F1 B8F2
students B1F1 B1F7 B9F5-B9F6
Students for a Democratic Society B10F5
Sukarno B3F1
Supreme Court B1F3 B5F6 B6F5 B7F1 B7F6 B8F6-B9F1 B10F3
Taft Hartley Act B5F1
taxes B1F1 B2F4 B3F5 B3F7 B5F4 B7F3 B8F1-B8F2 B8F4 B9F5
Taylor, Maxwell B2F3 B2F6-B3F1 B3F4
teachers B8F3
Teamsters B7F3
television B2F2 B3F3 B3F5 B4F1 B5F1-B5F3 B6F4 B7F3 B10F4
Temple, Shirley B8F2 B8F5
Thant, U. B2F1 B2F6 B3F3 B7F3 B7F5-B7F6 B10F3
Thieu, Nguyen Van B8F1 B8F5 B9F1 B10F5
Thurmond, Strom B10F5
tobacco industry B1F4 B1F7 B5F3 B8F2
trade B1F6 B2F4 B5F5 B7F5
Truman, Harry S. B6F2 B10F3 B10F5
U.S. Dollar B9F3
U.S. Flag B7F6
Ulbricht, Walter B2F3
unions B2F3 B3F4 B6F1 B7F3 B8F1 B10F4
United Nations B2F1 B2F6-B3F2 B3F5 B6F6 B7F5-B7F6 B9F4 B10F3
University of California B2F6 B3F3 B5F5
urban problems B3F7 B7F4 B8F5-B8F6 B9F3 B10F1
USS Pueblo B9F1-B9F2 B10F1 B10F3
Valenti, Jack B5F4
Verwoerd, Hendrik Frensch B6F3
Vietnam War SEE ALL FOLDERS
Von Braun, Werhner B6F3
voting rights B3F1 B3F3-B3F4 B3F8-B4F1 B5F4
Wallace, George B1F5-B1F6 B3F3-B3F4 B7F4-B7F5 B8F5-B9F1 B9F3 B10F1-B10F5
Wallace, Lurleen B6F4 B7F4
War on Poverty B1F5-B1F6 B2F2 B3F8 B5F4 B6F1 B6F3 B6F5-B6F6 B7F2 B8F1 B8F5-B8F6
Warren Commission B2F3 B6F5 B7F5
Warren, Earl B9F6-B10F1
Watts (Los Angeles) B4F4 B5F3 B7F1 B7F6-B8F1
Wayne, John B6F5
Weaver, Robert C. B5F1
welfare B9F3 B10F1
Weltner, Charles B6F4
Westmoreland, William C. B9F3
White, Edward H. B3F6
White, F. Clifton B9F4
White, Theodore B8F4
Williams, John J. B1F6
Wilson, Harold B2F4 B3F1 B6F1 B8F5
Yorty, Sam B3F8 B5F3 B5F5-B6F1 B6F4 B7F5-B8F1 B8F4 B8F6 B9F3 B9F6 B10F7
Young Republicans B4F4 B5F2
Zedong, Mao B1F5 B2F2 B2F5 B4F1 B4F4-B5F3 B5F5 B6F1 B6F3 B6F5-B7F1